# **Alexis Biver**

biver.alexis@proton.me

www.github.com/alexisbiver

Metz, Grand Est, France linkedin.com/in/biver-alexis

Machine Learning Engineer with over 5 years of experience in Research and Developpement for domains such as Robotics and Natural Language Processing (NLP).

Curious and eager to learn, I love to apply the latest techniques to develop new solutions for any domain.

#### CORE SKILLS

- Programming & Tools: Python, Torch, Docker, FASTApi, ONNX, C++, TS, MySQL, ROS
- Machine Learning: Motion prediction, NLP, Edge-device Optimization, Diffusion Models
- Languages: French (Native), English (Professional Working Proficiency)

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Machine Learning Engineer

Nancy, Grand Est, France

Inria, Team Larsen/HuCeBot Jan 2023 – Dec 2024 (2 years)

- Developed an open-source Python library for trajectory prediction in robotics
- Performed benchmarks and implementations of the SOTA solutions for the library
- Supervised an internship leading to a software allowing simple controls of a humanoid robot by voice

# Teaching Associate

Nancy, Grand Est, France

 $IUT\ Nancy-Charlemagne$  March 2024 – June 2024 (1 semester)

- Delivered lectures and practical sessions on "Introduction to Network Services" for first-year IT students.
- Conducted Java-based exercises and evaluations.

#### Machine Learning Engineer

Vivoka, R&D

Metz, France

Sept 2019 - Jan 2023 (3 years, 4 months)

- Designed and optimized ML models for embedded/edge devices using PyTorch and ONNX.
- Developed Python APIs to serve ML solutions and ensured production readiness.
- Conducted research, benchmarking, and technical popularization of scientific advancements.
- Enhanced data collection and processing to train robust NLP models.

#### Data Analyst Developer (Internship)

Luxembourg

PwC Luxembourg, Data Services March 2019 – Aug 2019 (6 months)

- Executed reporting and data visualization using ETL tools and Power BI.
- Updated data-mining solutions in C#.
- Researched and implemented a natural language understanding (NLU) approach for data augmentation.

## **EDUCATION**

# Master's in Natural Language Processing

Institut des sciences du Digital, Management et Cognition (IDMC)

2017-2019

Bachelor's in Mathematics and Computer Science

Université de Lorraine 2014–2017